Hello World Wide Web.

The ultimate loss is when the value of one's life fails a null check.

My name is Hosam Mohamed Nasr. I am a 29 years old Sudanese software engineer with 9 years worth of experience working on enterprise-scale applications/ projects. Looking to write code that makes a difference.

Education:

Bachelor of Computer Engineering(2013)

I hold a **BS. C** degree in **Computer Engineering** from the **Future University** of Sudan(Khartoum).

Languages:

Arabic is my mother tongue. I speak **English** fluently.

Skills:

Working as a **web designer**, **fullstack web developer** and **cross-platform mobile apps developer** I picked up some skills.

-Technical skills:

- I am a JavaScript expert. I use vanilla JS with jQuery for small projects, TypeScript with Angular/Vue.js for large web projects and ionic for mobile apps. I also use Nodejs / ExpressJS for backend apps.
- I have been using C# for my backend application for 4 years now. I like how reliable
 having a strongly typed language in the backend is. I also like to work with the code-first
 Database approach that Entity framework offers. In recent years I also used Nodejs for its
 flexibility and scalability.
- I used to work with the AMP Stack(Apache-MySqI-PHP).
- I am familiar with **CSS**, **SCSS**. The principles of user interface(**UI**), user experience(**UX**) design.
- To my utter surprise I loved **Tailwind.css**.
- I have various projects that involve WordPress.

Founder, Creator. Software Engineer

-Non-technical skills:

- I like to think that I am a **creator**. I build technical products from abstract ideas.
- I have experience **leading** development teams.
- I am a good **communicator**. Such skills helped me with positions where I was working remotely.

The difference.

What I bring to the table.

- Technical know-how. My years of Experience allow me to contribute technically to projects of all sizes.
- A team member. With active Contributions to discussions And decision-making.
- An owner. I own the projects I contribute to and act accordingly.

What am I looking for?

- The Room where it happens. A place where you can write code to make a sensible difference.
- A friendly workplace culture. In which opinions and contributions are welcome and hierarchy isn't a factor.
- Task-based accountability. I believe performance-not hours- is all that matters.

Experience:

-Senior Software Engineer@Zid Riyadh, SA(2022-Present)

Since July I have been working with Zid to better the e-commerce experience for thousands of merchants who rely on the platform. In this role I work exclusively with front end apps using JS for the most part. This role introduced me to Vue.js and Tailwind.css.

-Lead FullStack Developer@GLT Riyadh, SA(2021-2022)

I am leading a team that works across different projects under the umbrella of the holding company GLT. We design websites, create web apps and engineer APIs.

-Lead IT Product Manager @Mohtwize Riyadh, SA(2021-2021)

I am leading the IT product team at Riyadh based podcast platform Mohtwize starting April 2021. Here we are building products that empower podcast content creators in their mission to make their voices heard.

-Founder/ CTO @Rays Khartoum, SD(2019-2021)

I founded Rays to house a group of projects that I believe will change the way people accomplish their day-to-today tasks in Sudan. The first being Flex.

Hosam Nasr

Founder, Creator. Software Engineer

-Fullstack Web Developer @Homoola Riyadh, SA(2017-2019)

My job in homoola includes leading the front-end development team, assisting the backend development team, participating in the design of all technical products and shaping the technical road-map for the team.

-CTO @Shoghol Riyadh, SA(2016-2017)

Joined Riyadh-based startup shoghol in 2016 as chief technology officer. Working out of Badir Technology Incubators we built a platform for job seekers with emphasis on startups and freshers.

-Freelance Web Developer/ Software Engineer (2016-Present)

I started working as a freelancer in 2016 after quitting my job. Since then I have taken part in technical projects around the world.

-Web Designer @Isama Riyadh, SA(2015-2016)

I moved to Riyadh to join the Riyadh-based Isama in 2015. Working as a web designer I was in charge of transforming the clients' visions into websites.

Projects:

-Karrib(2019)

During the Sudanese revelation of December we felt the need of a technical solution to address the fake news epidemic and misleading propaganda that threatened the people's aspirations for democracy. Our answer was www.karrib.com. It has since become my personal testament of the impact technology can have on the region.

"Sudanese fact-checking platform Karrib, which relies on crowdsourcing to submit reports of false and fabricated stories and verify them, also countered misinformation and disinformation during the revolution. While it relies on crowdsourcing, moderators still have an influence over the final decision. The platform also runs no ads, and it has a comment section for people to share their opinions about each published report."

-Global Voices

Hosam Nasr

Founder, Creator. Software Engineer

-Tblya.com(2022)

Tblya.com was my attempt to make an e-store builder product that employs simplicity to offer a pleasant user experience. What started as an educational project(was aiming to enhance my understanding of node.js) became a side project that you can see at: www.tblya.com.

-Flex(2020)

Moving the city around. Flex is on a mission to fill the gap with last mile delivery in Sudan by providing a fast on-demand intercity and intercity delivery service. Flex is set to change the way people move things around Khartoum relying on an IOS/Android mobile apps for users and drivers, a matching system that automatically matches drivers and orders based on location, Rating/Goods Value and availability.

-Nyqat(2018)

Nyqat was a platform for Arabic content writers. It allowed any writer to contribute original content and get paid according to the revenue the content he writes would generate. The aim was to enrich Arabic content on the web by providing writers with incentives and a boosted sense of ownership.

For more Please visit my portfolio at me1o.github.io

Contact:

Call, Email or find me on social media.

Khartoum, SD - Riyadh, SA Mobile: 00249963056666 Email: hos4am@live.com LinkedIn: In/Hos4am

Twitter: @hos4am

